

# MOHAMMED NABRIS

## FITOUT, MEP & CIVIL QUANTITY SURVEYOR/ ESTIMATOR

Riyadh, Saudi Arabia

■ Sri Lanka

03/06/1995

Immediately Available with Transferrable Iqama

#### PROFILE

I am a cost and commercial professional with over 07 years of experience gained in pre- and post-contract stages with a fastpaced construction company that allows me to further enhance my skills, support the team and contribute my abilities to handle contracts & commercial activities. Held commercial positions responsible for overseeing and managing the commercial aspects of different types of construction projects in Saudi Arabia, Qatar and Sri Lanka. Moreover, having good knowledge of claims in order to improve the safety of project management.

### **EDUCATION**

2024 Birmingham, **United Kingdom**  BSc. (Hons)® in Quantity Surveying (Accredited by RICS) Reading

Birmingham City University

06/2015 - 06/2017 Sri Lanka

Pearson BTEC Level 5 Higher National Diploma in Quantity Surveying and Construction **Economics** 

**BCAS Campus** 

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

01/2024 - 07/2024 Jeddah, Saudi Arabia

#### **CRC INTERIOR FITOUT**

COST ESTIMATOR ENGINEER

- Study tender documents and drawings to be estimated and gather local & international supplier's proposals & specifications
- .Prepare RFQ submissions and send it to suppliers and subcontractors.
- Assess suppliers and sub-contractors' quotations to confirm whether the scope is covered and create a table to compare variations quoted prices and specifications.
- Conduct studies to estimate the overall project cost (i.e. material, labors, administrative expenses) from the revised bill of quantities to determine if a project is profitable and if company should bid for this project.
- Prepare estimation proposal and present it by assembling and displaying numerical and descriptive information also computation of costs by analyzing labor, material, and time requirements.
- Create a realistic cost database and maintain it by entering data (Vendors & cost) and Keep Updating the Fit-out, wooden joinery, and furniture materials Cost from the Local and international Market.
- Coordinate with our execution site team and subcontractors to ensure accurate implementation of BOO quantities and specifications.
- Conduct site visits to assess project progress and address any variation issues.

01/2021 - 11/2023 Oatar

### **Qatartrack International L.L.C**

MEP Quantity Surveyor PROJECT: New Naval Base **CLIENT: Qatar Air Force** PROJECT VALUE: 3.6 Billion QAR

- Take off Quantities based for MEP works.
- Expertly analyzed project specifications and drawings.
- Prepared and submitted Interim Payment Applications (IPA) including all necessary supporting documents to facilitate timely financial processing.
- Measure the value the work done on-site.
- Preparations of Subcontractor's package for RFQ
- Collaborated with Senior Quantity Surveyors in analyzing and updating rates in the Bill of Quantities (BOQ).
- Check and Review, analysis and recommendation of variations.
- Preparing Variations Along with IFC Drawing and Tender Documents.
- Conducted thorough reviews and certification of subcontractor invoices.

01/2018 - 12/2020 Qatar

### **HUB Contracting & Trading Co WLL-(URBACON TRADING AND CONTRACTING)**

**Quantity Surveyor** 

PROJECT: Design & Build of Lusail Palace CLIENT: Private Engineering Office (PEO) PROJECT VALUE: 4.8 Billion QAR

- Evaluating Sub-Contractor / Supplier payment applications and issuing Payment certificate
- Preparation of the Interim Payment Application.
- Preparation of quantity take-off and BOQ based on latest drawings.
- Identify and calculate the variation and pricing as per instruction of client.
- Preparation of subcontractor packages for procurement purposes.
- Review and evaluate subcontractor invoices, prepare payment certificate & close out the final accounts.
- Preparation of the Variation Order for subcontractor.
- Visit the site for verifying subcontractor actual work done.
- Maintaining commercial & contractual log for record.
- Co-ordinate with SQS to prepare Subcontractor Agreement.
- Sending RFQs and collecting quotations to prepare CBS.

12/2016 – 12/2017 Sri Lanka

## **Squire Mech Engineering (Pvt) Ltd**

**Assistant Quantity Surveyor** 

PROJECT: Typical Government school, accommodation and playground

CLIENT : Education Ministry of Sri Lanka PROJECT VALUE : 300 Million LKR

- Review Tender Documents (Drawing, BOQ, Spec)
- RFI for Missing Item to the main contractor
- Send inquiry for Quotation for new items
- Taking-off and BOQ Preparation
- Studying Procurement Route and Tendering Methods
- Prepare lists of the site needs (material, workers, technicians).
- Calculate the remuneration of the subcontractors, workers, equipment's,...etc.
- Prepare the detailed reports describing the situation of the items quantities, (plus or minus the contract BOQ)

<b>♦ LANGUAGES</b>							
English	● ● ● ● Tamil	• • • • •					
ARABIC	• • • •						
	C COLLMADE CALLS						

- AutoCAD
- Plan swift
- MS office

# PRO SKILLS

- Site supervision
- Financial Management
- Estimating Techniques
- Quality Assurance
- Engineering concepts
- Professional manners
- Communication
- Team Work & Coordination
- Problem solving

<b>D E</b>	~ :			-
DΕ	C. L	AK	AII	ON

I declare the information furnished herein are true to the best of my knowledge and in the event of being selected for employment.

**Mohammed Nabris**